projecteuclid.org 2019-11-21

# Project Euclid - mathematics and statistics online

## Privacy

Project Euclid is committed to protecting your privacy.

### Personal information that we may collect

Users of https://projecteuclid.org may be requested to provide personally identifiable information, including 

  * your name, address, email address, institutional affiliation, and telephone number
  * account credentials, such as username and password (Euclid staff cannot access passwords)
  * communications preferences, such as signing up to receive new publication email alerts

In our automated systems, we make efforts to collect only data that is necessary for Project Euclid to conduct business and improve user experience of our site. We may use analytics tools to help us understand aggregate user behaviors by collecting IP addresses, device and software identifiers, referring and exit URLs, onsite behavior and usage information, purchase history, and other similar information.

### How we collect your information

Individual users are required to provide their names and email addresses and create a password if they choose to create a MyEuclid account. Entering other information is optional. A user must create a MyEuclid account to register for individual subscription access to a publication or sign up for a table-of-contents email alert. A MyEuclid account is not necessary for other interaction with the Project Euclid website, including access to available content hosted by Project Euclid.

Project Euclid collects institutional account information, including IP (internet protocol) address ranges, publication entitlements, and administrative contact name and email address. The information is either provided to Project Euclid directly by the librarian account administrator or by a publisher who has collected the information from its institutional customer in order to fulfill an order or request.

Our website uses cookies, small data files placed on your device, to support some features. This is a common practice for websites across the internet, but if you would prefer that we not use cookies, you can set your browser to reject them. Disabling cookies on Project Euclid would disrupt a user’s ability to log in as an individual or library account holder, access individual subscriptions, or access pay-per-view purchases. Our site also uses cookies to accurately measure and report on usage for libraries.

### How we use your information

The information that you supply to Project Euclid will be used to verify your identity, confirm your content access, and provide services you explicitly request. It may be used to improve our response to customer service requests or enhance the services that we provide.

### How we share your information

Project Euclid may reveal personally identifiable information about you to third parties in order to facilitate a transaction that you have authorized; to comply with the law; to fulfill valid business needs in cooperation with our vendors, service providers, or agents (e.g., analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, processing orders, etc.).

Access to personal data is restricted to personnel who have a valid business reason for their access. Information may be made available to the publishers of the journals and monographs to which you or your institution subscribe.

### External websites

The Project Euclid website contains links to third-party websites. Project Euclid is not responsible for the content on third-party sites or for their use of personal information.

### How we protect your information

Project Euclid uses TLS/SSL (i.e., HTTPS) to provide data security and integrity throughout our site. Project Euclid never stores credit card numbers and will never ask you to supply credit card information over email or any other insecure method.

### To delete your account or change your preferences

If you sign up to receive email alerts from Project Euclid, you may use the links at the bottom of any email that you receive from us to opt out at any time or to change your preferences.

Unless you instruct us otherwise, you may, very occasionally, be included on a mailing list about a topic that we have reason to believe is related to your interests. If you do not want to receive any mailings from Project Euclid, please contact us to let us know.

To delete your MyEuclid account or submit any special requests or questions related to personal information and privacy, please contact us.

### Special notice for EU residents

If you are located within the European Economic Area, please see the chart below for more information about our privacy practices as is required by the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Project Euclid collects and maintains personal information about site users and purchasers of items to facilitate purchases and respond to your comments and questions. We may also use your information to keep you informed about Project Euclid products that we think may interest you. Please contact [gdpr@projecteuclid.org](mailto:gdpr@projecteuclid.org) with any questions, concerns, or requests.

Category of Personal Data | Purposes of Processing | Legal Bases for Processing  
---|---|---  
**Contact Information**  
including your name, home address, email address, and phone number  | To provide confirmations of transactions, respond to requests for information from you, and provide you with information regarding Project Euclid events and initiatives; to respond to records requests | 

  * To process transactions requested by you and meet our contractual obligations
  * Legitimate interests
  * Your consent, if applicable

**Payment Information**  
including your payment card number  | To process your transactions | 

  * To process transactions requested by you and meet our contractual obligations
  * Legitimate interests
  * Your consent, if applicable
